<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Tour Guide</string>
    <string name="header">Tour Guide</string>
    <string name="welcome">Welcome to the Tour Guide App! Select a city above to learn more about it.</string>
    <string-array name="cities">
        <item>Calgary</item>
        <item>Victoria</item>
        <item>Vancouver</item>
        <item>Toronto</item>
        <item>Halifax</item>
        <item>Montreal</item>
        <item>Fredericton</item>
    </string-array>
    <string name="Calgary">Calgary is the largest city in the prairie province of Alberta.
        Calgary was named after Calgary Castle on the Isle of Mull in Scotland. The Indigenous
        peoples of Southern Alberta refer to the Calgary area as \"elbow\", in reference to the
        sharp bend made by the Bow River and the Elbow River. While the oil and gas industry
        comprise an important part of the economy, the city has invested a great deal into other
        areas such as tourism and high-tech manufacturing. Over 3.1 million people now visit the
        city annually for its many festivals and attractions, especially the Calgary Stampede.
        Calgary has the sunniest days year-round of Canada\'s 100 largest cities, with slightly
        over 332 days of sun. Thunderstorms can be frequent and sometimes severe with most of
        them occurring in the summer months. Calgary lies within Alberta\'s Hailstorm Alley and
        is prone to damaging hailstorms every few years.
    </string>
    <string name="Victoria">Victoria is the capital city of British Columbia. Named for Queen
        Victoria, the city is one of the oldest in the Pacific Northwest, with British settlement
        beginning in 1843. The city has retained a large number of its historic buildings, in
        particular its two most famous landmarks, the Parliament Buildings and the Empress Hotel.
        The city\'s Chinatown is the second oldest in North America, after that of San Francisco.
        The region\'s Coast Salish First Nations peoples established communities in the area long
        before European settlement. Known as \"the Garden City\", Victoria is an attractive city
        and a popular tourism destination. Canada Day fireworks displays, Symphony Splash, and
        many other music festivals and cultural events draw tens of thousands of Greater
        Victorians and visitors to the downtown core. The Rifflandia and Electronic Music
        Festival are other music events that draw crowds to the downtown core. Every year, the
        Swiftsure International Yacht Race attracts boaters from around the world to participate
        in the boat race in the waters off of Vancouver Island, and the Victoria Dragon Boat
        Festival brings over 90 teams from around North America. The Tall Ships Festival brings
        sailing ships to the city harbour. Victoria also hosts the start of the Vic-Maui Yacht Race.
    </string>
    <string name="Vancouver">Vancouver is a coastal city in the Lower Mainland of British
        Columbia. It is known for beautiful mountain scenery, cultural diversity, and stunning
        waterfront. It has been consistently ranked one of the most livable cities in Canada and
        in the world. Indigenous settlement of Vancouver began more than 10,000 years ago and
        included the Squamish, Musqueam, and Tsleil-Waututh peoples. While forestry remains its
        largest industry, Vancouver is well known as an urban centre surrounded by nature. A
        collection of Edwardian buildings in the city\'s old downtown core were, in their day,
        the tallest commercial buildings in the British Empire. These were, in succession, the
        Carter-Cotton Building, the Dominion Building, and the Sun Tower (the former two at
        Cambie and Hastings Streets and the latter at Beatty and Pender Streets). Vancouver has
        been called a \"city of neighbourhoods.\" Each neighbourhood in Vancouver has a distinct
        character and ethnic mix. People of English, Scottish, and Irish origins were
        historically the largest ethnic groups in the city, and elements of British society and
        culture are still visible in some areas, particularly South Granville and Kerrisdale.
        Germans are the next-largest European ethnic group in Vancouver and were a leading force
        in the city\'s society and economy until the rise of anti-German sentiment with the
        outbreak of World War I in 1914. Today the Chinese are the largest visible ethnic group
        in Vancouver; the city has a diverse Chinese-speaking community with speakers of several
        dialects, notably Cantonese and Mandarin. Neighbourhoods with distinct ethnic commercial
        areas include Chinatown, Punjabi Market, Little Italy, Greektown, and (formerly) Japantown.
    </string>
    <string name="Toronto">Toronto is the most populous city in Canada and the capital city of
        Ontario. The diverse population of Toronto reflects its current and historical role as an
        important destination for immigrants to Canada. About half of its residents were born
        outside of Canada, and over 200 ethnic origins are represented among its inhabitants.
        Toronto is a prominent centre for music, theatre, motion picture production, and
        television production. Toronto is known for its many skyscrapers and high-rise buildings,
        in particular the tallest free-standing structure on land outside of Asia, the CN Tower.
        Indigenous peoples have travelled through and inhabited the Toronto area for more than
        10,000 years. After the broadly disputed Toronto Purchase, when the Mississauga
        surrendered the area to the British Crown, the British established the town of York in
        1793 and later designated it as the capital of Upper Canada. York was renamed and
        incorporated in 1834 as the city of Toronto. It was designated as the capital of the
        province of Ontario in 1867 during Canadian Confederation.
    </string>
    <string name="Halifax">Halifax is the capital and most populous municipality of the Canadian
        province of Nova Scotia. The Mi\'kmaq name for Halifax is Kjipuktuk, pronounced
        \"che-book-took\". The name means \"Great Harbour\" in the Mi\'kmaq language. Halifax is a
        major cultural centre within the Atlantic provinces. The municipality has maintained many
        of its maritime and military traditions, while opening itself to a growing multicultural
        population. The municipality\'s urban core also benefits from a large population of
        post-secondary students who strongly influence the local cultural scene. Halifax has a
        number of art galleries, theatres and museums, as well as most of the region\'s
        national-quality sports and entertainment facilities. Halifax is also the home to many of
        the region\'s major cultural attractions, such as Halifax Pop Explosion, Symphony Nova
        Scotia, the Art Gallery of Nova Scotia, The Khyber, the Maritime Museum of the Atlantic
        and the Neptune Theatre. The region is noted for the strength of its music scene and
        nightlife, especially within the urban communities.
    </string>
    <string name="Montreal">Montreal is the largest city in the province of Quebec. Founded in
        1642 as Ville-Marie, or \"City of Mary\", it is now named after Mount Royal, the
        triple-peaked mountain around which the early settlement was built. French is the city\'s
        official language. In the Ojibwe language, the land is called Mooniyaang, which was \"the
        first stopping place\" in the Ojibwe migration story. Archaeological evidence in the
        region indicates that First Nations native people occupied the island of Montreal as
        early as 4,000 years ago. The Saint Lawrence Iroquoians established the village of
        Hochelaga at the foot of Mount Royal two centuries before the French arrived. Montreal
        was the capital of the Province of Canada from 1844 to 1849, but lost its status when a
        Tory mob burnt down the Parliament building to protest the passage of the Rebellion
        Losses Bill. In 2006, Montreal was named a UNESCO City of Design, one of only three
        design capitals in the world. The Underground City (officially RÉSO), an important
        tourist attraction, is an underground network connecting shopping centres, pedestrian
        thoroughfares, universities, hotels, restaurants, bistros, subway stations and more, in
        and around downtown. The city is composed of 19 large boroughs, subdivided into
        neighbourhoods. Many of these boroughs were independent cities that were forced to merge
        with Montreal in January 2002 following the 2002 municipal reorganization of Montreal.
    </string>
    <string name="Fredericton">Fredericton is the capital city of New Brunswick. The city hosts
        the annual Harvest Jazz and Blues Festival, attracting regional and international jazz,
        blues, rock, and world artists. The city also hosts the Garrison Night Market through the
        summer months which showcases many local vendors and artists and musicians. Fredericton
        is also an important and vibrant centre point for the region\'s top visual artists; many
        of New Brunswick\'s notable artists live and work there today. Fredericton has also been
        home to some great historical Canadian painters as well, including Goodridge Roberts, and
        Molly and Bruno Bobak. As a provincial capital, its economy is tied to the public sector;
        however, the city also contains a growing IT and commercial sector. The city has the
        highest percentage of residents with post-secondary education in the province and the
        highest per capita income of any city in New Brunswick. There is archaeological evidence
        of a camp in the area 12,000 years ago, and the Wolastoqiyik farmed several kilometres
        upriver. Colonists from the Kingdom of France in the late 1600s built Fort Nashwaak on
        the north side of the Saint John River, as the capital of Acadia.
    </string>
</resources>

